Mss.Rec.41 Mss.Rec.41
American Philosophical Society
Materials Recorded at Copper Center, Alaska
1960
Mss.Rec.41
American Philosophical Society
9.0 Reel(s)
Field recordings made in Chistochina and Copper Center, Alaska in 1960. Includes potlatch songs, love songs, Christmas tree songs, sorry songs, dance songs, and others. Some songs Yakutat Tlingit, Upper Tanana, or Tanacross. Also includes some Ahtna vocabulary.
9 sound tape reels (6 hr., 22 min.): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Frederica de Laguna and accessioned in 1962 (1961 961r).
Conditions Governing Access
Permission required for access to materials. Please consult the Manuscripts Librarian for details.
Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Ethnomusicology--Alaska; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Northern Tutchone language; Songs.; Sound recordings; Tanacross language; Tlingit language; Upper Tanana language
- Audio recordings
  - Songs and conversation at Chistochina, Alaska, July 22, 1960 [1 of 2], 1960-07-22; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:26; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Herbie; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; John, Steven; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Adam; Sanford, Frieda; Sanford, Howard; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Mary; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyon, Paul
    Scope and Contents note
    Songs, discussion of songs, and conversation.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Songs and conversation at Chistochina, Alaska, July 22, 1960 [2 of 2], 1960-07-22; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:22; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Herbie; Joe, Maggie; John, Lucy; John, Steven; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Adam; Sanford, Frieda; Sanford, Howard; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Mary; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyon, Paul
    Songs, discussion of songs, and conversation. Kate Sanford is the main singer and drummer.
  - Songs and conversation at Chistochina, Alaska, July 23, 1960 [1 of 2], 1960-07-23; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:33; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Herbie; Joe, Maggie; John, Kitty; John, Robert; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Howard; Sinyon, Paul
  - Songs and conversation at Chistochina, Alaska, July 23, 1960 [2 of 2], 1960-07-23; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:48; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Herbie; Joe, Maggie; John, Kitty; John, Robert; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Howard; Sinyon, Paul
    Two potlatch songs, with conversation. Recording ends with summary information and corrections by Frederica de Laguna. "The potlatch song is sung when everybody stands and sways from side to side, arms folded, and wishes for good luck. Each potlatch song is composed for a special occasion, and is sung once at the potlatch by the assembly. It then becomes the property of the host's clan and may not be sung by another clan unless they pay for it - $10-20."
  - Yakutat Song: Chinaman Song, 1960-07-27; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:33; Charley, Tenas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Lincoln, Sophia; McClellan, Catharine
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tlingit language
  - Northway Song, 1960-07-27; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:56; Charley, Tenas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Lincoln, Sophia
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Upper Tanana language
  - Yakutat Song, 1960-07-27; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:37; Charley, Tenas; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Lincoln, Louise; Lincoln, Sophia
  - Gospel Hymn: Only Trust Him, 1960-07-27; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:59; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Lincoln, Sophia
  - sARani Eating Song, 1960-08-13; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:34; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
    "This song is apparently one sung by guests at a potlatch after they have been fed. In it they claim they have eaten as gluttonousely as the crows of the song." The song is played twice, the second time with a different microphone.
  - Fred Billy Banzanita's Love Song, 1960-08-13; 03-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:47; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
  - Tanacross Dance Song, 1960-08-13; 03-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:51; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; John, Lucy; Sanford, Kate
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tanacross language
  - Snatches of Songs, 1960-08-13; 03-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:18; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; John, Lucy; Sinyone, Jim
  - Christmas Tree Song, 1960-07-27; 03-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:08; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph; Sinyone, Jim
  - HaiyuwE Song, 1960-08-13; 03-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:34; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; John, Lucy; Sanford, Kate
    "This is the song to which a masked man dances to frighten naughty children at potlatch time. He is generally compared to Santa Claus."
  - Sunday Morning, 1960-08-13; 03-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:58; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; John, Lucy; Sanford, Kate; Sanford, Ralph
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tlingit language
  - Sanford Teddy's Sorry Song, 1960-08-13; 03-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:16; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Sanford, Kate
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Upper Tanana language
  - Dawson Hanging Song, 1960-08-14; 03-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:31; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Han language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Short song, 1960-08-14; 03-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:38; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
  - Duck Foot Song, 1960-08-14; 03-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:45; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Phonograph Sorry Song, 1960-08-14; 03-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:28; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska
  - Kate Sanford's Sorry Song for Mother, 1960-08-14; 03-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:15; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Sanford, Kate
  - Sorry Song for Chief Peter, 1960-08-14; 03-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:09; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Sanford, Kate
    This song later re-recorded due to poor current to recording machine. See Related Recording.
  - Sorry Song for Mentasta John, 1960-08-14; 03-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:23; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate
  - Owl Song, Brush Indian Song, and Mentasta John's Sorry Song, 1960-08-14; 03-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:42; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate
  - Frank Charley's Sorry Song, 1960-08-14; 03-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:37; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Ring Charley's Sorry Song, 1960-08-14; 03-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:19; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate; Sinyone, Jim
  - Annie Tyone's Love Song, Jim Tyone's Love Song, and 'Engi Song, 1960-08-14; 03-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:56; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
  - Joking Songs, 1960-08-14; 03-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:21; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
  - She married the Wrong Man, 1960-08-14; 03-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:51; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Herbie; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Love songs
  - You're not my Sweetheart, 1960-08-14; 03-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; McClellan, Catharine; Sanford, Kate
  - A Tlingit Song and Snatches of Potlatch Songs and Cries, 1960-08-14; 03-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:24; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
  - Christmas Day, New Years Day, 1960-08-14; 03-27; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:40; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Christmas music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Christmas Tree, 1960-08-14; 03-28; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:45; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Christmas trees--Songs and music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Too Much Johnson, 1960-08-14; 03-29; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
  - Northway Dance Song, 1960-08-14; 03-30; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:12; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Kate
    Tape runs out before completion of song.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Chistochina (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Potlatch--Alaska
  - Ahtna Vocabulary, 1960-07-30; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:18; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; McKinley, Jim
    Ahtena language; Chistochina (Alaska)
  - History of Lt. Allen, who came up the Copper River, and story of Bacille and the massacre of the Russian Expedition on the Upper Copper River [1 of 2], 1960-08-01; 05-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:49; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille
    Ahtena Indians--History; Alaska--History--1867-1959; Allen, Henry T. (Henry Tureman), 1859-1930; Copper Center (Alaska); Massacres--Alaska--19th century; Russians--Alaska--History--19th century
  - Story of Bacille and the massacre of the Russian Expedition on the Upper Copper River [2 of 2], 1960-08-01; 05-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:26:52; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille
    Ahtena Indians--History; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Alaska--History--1867-1959; Copper Center (Alaska); Massacres--Alaska--19th century; Russians--Alaska--History--19th century
  - How SArani gai made the world [1 of 3], 1960-08-11; 06-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:19; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille
    Primarily in English, with occasional Ahtna.
    Ahtena Indians--Folklore; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Creation--Mythology; Raven (Legendary character)--Legends
  - How SArani gai made the world [2 of 3], 1960-08-11; 06-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:32:22; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille
  - How SArani gai made the world [3 of 3], 1960-08-11; 07-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:33; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille
  - HaiyuwE Song, 1960-08-11; 07-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:10; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
    Song is repeated due to loudness of drums on first take.
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Old Copper River loving song, 1960-08-11; 07-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:43; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Love songs
  - Ahtna song, 1960-08-11; 07-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:36; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - tcElali song, 1960-08-11; 07-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:42; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
  - Up-the-Line Drinking Song, 1960-08-11; 07-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:41; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Drinking songs; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music
  - Old Chitina Love Song, 1960-08-11; 07-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:22; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; George, Bacille; George, Nancy; McClellan, Catharine
  - Tlingit Song, 1960-08-20; 08-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:02; Brown, Andy; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004
  - Duck's dAmba Song, 1960-08-27; 08-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:13; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Maggie
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Ahtena language; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Song to Catharine McClellan, 1960-08-27; 08-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Song to Frederica de Laguna, 1960-08-27; 08-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:00; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Money Sorry Song, 1960-08-27; 08-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:05; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    "Words mean: 'That money kill my daughter, I guess.'"
  - Gulkana River Sorry Song and Dance Song, 1960-08-27; 08-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:40; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    "Gulkana River some lady pull sled by the neck. She go after something. She drown."
  - Hu ha heya, 1960-08-27; 08-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:19; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Tetlin Sorry Song, 1960-08-27; 08-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:57; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Ralph
  - Gun Accident Song, 1960-08-27; 08-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:11; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Ralph
  - Tanacross Sorry Song, 1960-08-27; 08-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:14; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Tanacross language
  - T'u baRa Sorry Song, 1960-08-27; 08-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:55; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Mary
  - Ring Charley's Sorry Song, 1960-08-27; 08-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:23; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Ralph
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs; Mourning customs--United States--Alaska
  - Coming Up qAsqei, 1960-08-27; 08-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:36; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Ralph
  - Lake Song and Gunho Song, 1960-08-27; 08-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:45; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Dance Song, 1960-08-27; 08-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:02; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Ralph
  - Sleep Doctor's Song, 1960-08-27; 08-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:02; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill
  - Tanacross Sorry Song, 1960-08-27; 08-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:11; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie
  - Santa Claus Coming, 1960-08-27; 08-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Ralph
  - Stranger Song, 1960-08-27; 08-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:34; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Joe, Bill; Joe, Maggie; Sanford, Ralph
  - Children's Scare Songs, 1960-08-25; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:37; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Phonograph Sorry Song, 1960-08-25; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:10; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Muskrat Man Song ("She married the wrong man"), 1960-08-25; 09-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:56; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Paul Joe's Sorry Song for Chief Peter, 1960-08-25; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:20; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
    Made for the Potlatch of Chief Peter Tetlin, September 1958. Re-recording of song recorded earlier in the month. See Related Recording.
  - First Sorry Song for Chief John, 1960-08-25; 09-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:22; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Second Sorry Song for Chief John, 1960-08-25; 09-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:01; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Engi Song, 1960-08-25; 09-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:20; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Frank Charley's Song for Sanford Charley, 1960-08-25; 09-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:34; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - You're Not my Sweetheart, 1960-08-25; 09-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:51; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Potlatch Songs & Cries, 1960-08-25; 09-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:53; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Ring Charley's Sorry Song, 1960-08-25; 09-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:14; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Fox's Hunting Song, 1960-08-25; 09-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:50; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Wolf's Hunting Song, 1960-08-25; 09-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:57; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Wolverine's Hunting Song, 1960-08-25; 09-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:32; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - SARani gai's Fishing Song, 1960-08-25; 09-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:52; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
    "This is the song sung by sARani gai when he lost his bill."
  - Groundsquirrel Song (1), 1960-08-25; 09-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:37; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Groundsquirrel Song (2), 1960-08-25; 09-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Groundsquirrel Song (3), 1960-08-25; 09-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Gene Nicolai's Song, 1960-08-25; 09-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:29; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Cook Inlet Paddle Song, 1960-08-25; 09-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:39; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
    Ahtena Indians--Music; Ahtena Indians--Social life and customs; Copper Center (Alaska); Dena'ina language; Indians of North America--Alaska--Music; Indians of North America--Alaska--Social life and customs
  - Another dAsnei Song, 1960-08-25; 09-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:42; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Third Dasnei (Cook Inlet) song, 1960-08-25; 09-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Love Song (incomplete), 1960-08-25; 09-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:45; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
    Tape runs out before completion of song. Re-recorded as subsequent program.
  - Love Song, 1960-08-25; 09-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:14; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
    Re-recording of previous song that was cut-off by ending of tape.
  - Tlingit Song, 1960-08-25; 09-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:52; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha
  - Copper River Dance Song, 1960-08-25; 09-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:58; De Laguna, Frederica, 1906-2004; Jackson, Arthur; Jackson, Martha